<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Water use | Academic</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/water-use/</link>
      <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/water-use/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Water use</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 Jonathan Ojeda</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>//localhost:1313/img/avatar</url>
      <title>Water use</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/tags/water-use/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards high water productivity in agriculture based on multi-scale modelling</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/project/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/project/project-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sustainable land and water management are faced with various challenges at the field, farm and larger regional and market scales. Natural resources are managed at field-scale but policy settings are usually regional or national. Likewise, the scalability of agricultural systems (i.e. methods used to integrate data and models at different scales) is often ignored or only partially represented. This project will investigate how water management impacts crop productivity regionally in Australia. We will apply existing model-scaling techniques and assess the drivers of yield variability for diverse Australian agricultural systems, and further contrast these results with those from a case study in Spain. This innovative research will combine strengths in irrigated agriculture at field-scale (TIA-UTAS) with multi-scale modeling, multi-model analysis (UoG-ZALF) and integrated biophysical-socio-economics assessments (ZALF). I will receive training from two German ECRs and transfer these new skills to Australia. Drs Rezaei and Kamali will extend the regional assessments and agro-hydrological modeling tested in Europe to new environments (Australia) as case studies their current projects. Together, with this new collaboration as a basis, we will develop methods that can support improved water risk management and plan with a better understanding of the drivers of yield variability and scaling methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;partners&#34;&gt;Partners:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;University of Göttingen (Prof Stefan Siebert, Dr Ehsan Eyshi Rezaei), Leibniz Centre for Agricultural Landscape Research (ZALF) (Dr Bahareh Kamali, Dr Heidi Webber, Dr Frank Ewert), Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;funded-by&#34;&gt;Funded by&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Australia-Germany Joint Research Co-operation Scheme, Universities Australia, German Academic Exchange Service (DAAD).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;grant-amount&#34;&gt;Grant amount&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AUD$40,360&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
