<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Crop Modelling | Academic</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/crop-modelling/</link>
      <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/crop-modelling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Crop Modelling</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 Jonathan Ojeda</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>//localhost:1313/img/avatar</url>
      <title>Crop Modelling</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/tags/crop-modelling/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crop-livestock adaptation to climate change based on modelling and remote-sensing</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/project/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/project/project-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Good livestock management and policies are crucial to maintaining economic stability while addressing the challenges of climate change. Yet the policies and practices guiding the industry vary by region and nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will assess how crop-livestock practices impact farm performance regionally under
different climate change scenarios. Coupling existing multiple-scaling and remote-sensing
techniques with advanced biophysical models we will evaluate drivers of yield variability for
feed systems in Argentina, Uruguay, and Australia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project will hold three workshops. The workshops aim to assess how crop-livestock management practices impact regional farming performance under different climate change scenarios. Technologies, which will be used to assess the yield variability for diverse forage cropping systems, include existing model-scaling and remote-sensing techniques developed in Argentina (the most advanced biophysical models in the world). These assessments will take place in Argentina, Uruguay, and Australia. The workshops will also strengthen crop-livestock management skills for the three countries in different areas: systems modeling (Australia), remote-sensing system (Argentina), and livestock systems analysis (Uruguay).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project will be conducted collaboratively with livestock industry decision-makers who will perform foresight exercises to explore alternative futures. This will facilitate the development of forage crop regional management and preparation for environmental impacts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;partners&#34;&gt;Partners&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;University of Southern Queensland (Australia), University of Buenos Aires (Argentina), University of Entre Rios (Argentina), Instituto Nacional de Investigación Agropecuaria (Uruguay), Association of Regional Consortiums of Agricultural Experimentation (Argentina and Uruguay)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;funded-by&#34;&gt;Funded by&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Council on Australia Latin America Relations (COALAR) Department of Foreign Affairs and Trade, Australian Government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;grant-amount&#34;&gt;Grant amount&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AUD$54,952&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lincoln University and P&amp;F</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/stays/lincoln/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/stays/lincoln/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;lucerne-workshop-and-potato-modelling-lincoln-new-zealand&#34;&gt;Lucerne Workshop and Potato Modelling, Lincoln, New Zealand&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;period&#34;&gt;Period&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8 Sep - 1 Oct 2019&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;activities&#34;&gt;Activities&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I participated in a 2-week workshop organized by Dr. Derrick Moot (Dryland Pastures Research Team) focused on lucerne eco-physiology and modeling. A group of more than 30 international researchers discussed how to better predict the behavior of this crop using current modeling tools. The main topics discussed during this workshop are listed below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Growth and development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview of current models being used. APSIM, STICS, HERMES.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phenology and canopy characteristics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dry matter accumulation and partitioning, fall dormancy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Soil water dynamics and modeling water stress effects on lucerne.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Soils, limiting situations, grazing and model applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nitrogen fixation/soil carbon and N dynamics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plant physiology, allometry, herbage quality, N dynamics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On-farm applications – examples for farm systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also spent one week at the Plant and Food Research Institute working with Dr. Hamish Brown. We focused our work on the analysis of crop model configuration using the potato APSIM model as a case study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;achievements&#34;&gt;Achievements&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paper under review &lt;em&gt;in-silico&lt;/em&gt; Plants&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;host-researchers-in-germany&#34;&gt;Host Researchers in Germany&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr Derrick Moot and Dr Hamish Brown&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;funded-by&#34;&gt;Funded by&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tasmanian Institute of Agriculture and Lincoln University&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Purdue University</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/stays/purdue/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/stays/purdue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;department-of-agronomy-purdue-university-west-lafayette-indiana-us&#34;&gt;Department of Agronomy, Purdue University, West Lafayette, Indiana, US&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;period&#34;&gt;Period&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From May 2015 to Mar 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;activities&#34;&gt;Activities&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I modified APSIM Classic so that it could accurately predict growth and yield of switchgrass and Miscanthus; two plant species that are not yet represented in this large, multi-species model. I altered two existing APSIM sub-models (lucerne, sugarcane) using knowledge of species-specific differences in growth, development and agronomic practices. In brief, the modifications for Miscanthus include radiation use efficiency and biomass partitioning. The modifications for Switchgrass were more extensive and included the thermal time calculation, biomass partitioning, radiation use efficiency, transpiration efficiency, temperature dependency of photosynthesis and the light extinction coefficient. I also assembled large databases for soils and weather that I could subsequently associate with site-specific yield data of both species and successfully calibrated and validated both of these new sub-models. These new APSIM sub-models predict the yield of both species across broad geographies from the East Coast to the Great Plains of the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I altered the APSIM maize model routine in substantive ways to predict corn yield in continuous corn and soybean-corn rotations. First, I successfully calibrated and validated the model using data from the Eastern corn belt of the US. I then used water flow and agronomic data from Purdue’s Water Quality Field Station (WQFS) to calibrate the water use/drainage sub-routine of water balance data that can be obtained. This enabled to make improvement in the APSIM maize model not otherwise possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;achievements&#34;&gt;Achievements&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Publications&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ojeda JJ, Volenec JJ, Brouder SM, Caviglia OP, Agnusdei MG (2017) Evaluation of Agricultural Production Systems Simulator (APSIM) as yield predictor of Panicum virgatum and Miscanthus x giganteus in several US environments. Global Change Biology Bioenergy. 9, 796-816. doi:10.1111/gcbb.12384&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ojeda JJ, Volenec JJ, Brouder SM, Caviglia OP, Agnusdei MG (2018) Modelling stover and grain yields, and subsurface artificial drainage from long-term corn rotations using APSIM. Agricultural Water Management. 195, 154-171. doi:10.1016/j.agwat.2017.10.010&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Model development&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Adaption of APSIM Sugar and Lucerne to represent Miscanthus and Switchgrass&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This code contains simulations of Sugar adapted to represent Miscanthus and Lucerne to represent Switchgrass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/APSIMInitiative/APSIMClassic/tree/master/Examples/BioEnergy&#34;&gt;https://github.com/APSIMInitiative/APSIMClassic/tree/master/Examples/BioEnergy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;host-researchers&#34;&gt;Host Researchers&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dr Jeffrey Volenec and Dr Sylvie Brouder (Purdue University)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;funded-by&#34;&gt;Funded by&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fulbright Fellowship, Fulbright Commission, United States&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;grant-amount&#34;&gt;Grant amount&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AUD $37,000&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University of Sydney and University of Tasmania</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/stays/uni-sydney-tas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/stays/uni-sydney-tas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;faculty-of-veterinary-science-the-university-of-sydney-camden-nsw-australia&#34;&gt;Faculty of Veterinary Science, The University of Sydney, Camden, NSW, Australia&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tasmanian-institute-of-agriculture-university-of-tasmania-burnie-tas-australia&#34;&gt;Tasmanian Institute of Agriculture, University of Tasmania, Burnie, TAS, Australia&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;period&#34;&gt;Period&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From October to December 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;activities&#34;&gt;Activities&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an APSIM trainee, I was a visiting scholar at the Dairy group of The University of Sydney in Camden and at the Tasmanian Institute of Agriculture, University of Tasmania. We used experimental field data collected in several locations of Argentina and Australia to evaluate the ability of APSIM Classic to simulate the growth patterns of annual and perennial forage crops and to predict dry matter yields in these regions. We also evaluated the APSIM ability to predict forage dry matter yield and water productivity of multiple continuous forage crop sequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;achievements&#34;&gt;Achievements&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two research collaborative papers published in high impact scientific journals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ojeda JJ, Pembleton KG, Islam MR, Agnusdei MG, Garcia SC (2016) Evaluation of the agricultural production systems simulator simulating Lucerne and annual ryegrass dry matter yield in the Argentine Pampas and south-eastern Australia. Agricultural Systems. 143, 61-75. Publication derived from my PhD thesis. doi:10.1016/j.agsy.2015.12.005&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ojeda JJ, Pembleton KG, Islam MR, Caviglia OP, Agnusdei MG, Garcia SC (2018) Modelling forage yield and water productivity of continuous crop sequences in the Argentinian Pampas. European Journal of Agronomy. 92, 84-96. Publication derived from PhD thesis. doi: 10.1016/j.eja.2017.10.004&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;host-researchers&#34;&gt;Host Researchers&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dr Keith Pembleton (Tasmanian Institute of Agriculture)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dr Rafiq Islam and Dr Sergio (Yani) Garcia (University of Sydney)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;funded-by&#34;&gt;Funded by&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Funded by INNOVA-T Grant and funding from INTA, The University of Sydney and University of Tasmania.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;grant-amount&#34;&gt;Grant amount&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AUD $15,000&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
