<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Phds | Academic</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/phd/</link>
      <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/phd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Phds</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 Jonathan Ojeda</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>//localhost:1313/img/avatar</url>
      <title>Phds</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/phd/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modelling the effects of farming intensification on the productivity, profitability, greenhouse gas emissions and ecosystems services in agroforestry and livestock systems</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/phd/demlie/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/phd/demlie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-demlie&#34;&gt;About Demlie&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demlie Zelelew obtained his bachelor’s degree in Soil and Water Management and Engineering at Haramaya University in Ethiopia and his master’s degree in Water Management and Environmental Engineering at Vienna University of Natural Resources and Life Sciences in Austria. Demlie has been working in an agricultural research institution in Ethiopia for the past ten years and his interest in research areas are agricultural water management, integrated water resources management, climate change, soil and water conservation, integrated watershed management, crop modeling, water pollution, soil acidity, and salinity management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demlie is now a Ph.D. candidate at the University of Tasmania in Australia, and he is seeking smart irrigation agriculture which has economical profitability and reduced trade-offs on ecosystem services by looking at productivity, greenhouse gas emissions, water use efficiency (water footprint) and selected soil and water quality indicating parameters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Contact:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:DemlieGebresellassie.Zelelew@utas.edu.au&#34;&gt;DemlieGebresellassie.Zelelew@utas.edu.au&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-the-project&#34;&gt;About the project&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project has the following objectives:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assess the land-use change of agroforestry and livestock farms and estimate its impact on GHG emissions and ecosystem services (e.g. N leaching) in Australia during the last three decades.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compare the greenhouse gas emissions, profit and productivity for different levels of intensification (stocking rate, fertilizer, irrigation) as the proportion of trees on agroforestry farm increases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quantify the effect to increase the area of trees on ecosystems services such as biodiversity, soil water (leakage) and soil nitrogen (nitrate leaching) for a gradient of intensification in agroforestry and livestock systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Estimate the effects of future climate change on GHG emission, productivity, profitability and trade-offs on ecosystems services of a gradient of intensification in agroforestry and livestock systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;location&#34;&gt;Location&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tasmanian Institute of Agriculture, University of Tasmania, Tasmania, Australia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;period&#34;&gt;Period&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From January 2020 to January 2024&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;supervisors&#34;&gt;Supervisors&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr Jonathan Ojeda, Dr Beth Penrose (primary supervisor), Dr Matt Harrison, Prof Caroline Mohammed (TIA-UTAS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;grant-amount&#34;&gt;Grant amount&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UTAS Tuition Fee: AUD$144,900&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tasmania Graduate Research Scholarship living allowance: AUD$108,328&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The benefits and limits of diversity in agricultural systems</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/phd/francesco/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/phd/francesco/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-francesco&#34;&gt;About Francesco&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Francesco is a PhD Student with the Tasmanian Institute of Agriculture of the University of Tasmania (UTAS) and CSIRO Agriculture and Food in Australia. With a background in environmental economics, his PhD research focuses on the environmental and socio-economic benefits of increasing biodiversity in different agricultural systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to starting his PhD, Francesco was a visiting researcher with the Institute for Conservation and Sustainable Development of the Amazon (IDESAM) in Brazil. He was involved in work that investigated ways to increase socio-economic benefits for local farming communities and the sustainability of farms by converting traditional coffee plantations to agroforestry systems in the Brazilian Amazon. Francesco has also worked as a research fellow for the Development Impact Unit of Bioversity International, one of the CGIAR centres, in Rome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Francesco enjoys playing basketball and guitar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Contact:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:Francesco.Tacconi@csiro.au&#34;&gt;Francesco.Tacconi@csiro.au&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-the-project&#34;&gt;About the project&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proposed research aims at exploring which type of diversification can provide the benefits discussed above and in which context it can be a solution to sustainable agriculture with the overarching research question being to what extent can the productivity, profitability, and sustainability of agricultural systems in Australia and globally benefit from being diverse? The two hypotheses to test and either providence evidence for or reject are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extensive/mixed agroecosystems are higher in diversity and/or more resilient to climate change than highly specialized systems, such as monocultures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increasing agricultural and tree biodiversity within the broader landscape will improve productivity, deliver ecosystem services, and improve rural livelihoods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;location&#34;&gt;Location&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;St. Lucia CSIRO, Brisbane, Australia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;period&#34;&gt;Period&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From June 2019 to June 2023&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;supervisors&#34;&gt;Supervisors&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr Jonathan Ojeda (Primary from UTAS), Dr Katharina Waha (CSIRO), Dr Peat Leith (TIA-UTAS)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;funded-by&#34;&gt;Funded by&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;University of Tasmania CSIRO and Australian Sustainable Agriculture Elite Scholarship (CSIRO-TIA/UTAS)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;grant-amount&#34;&gt;Grant amount&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Total: AUD$303,226&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UTAS Tuition Fee: AUD$144,900&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tasmania Graduate Research Scholarship and CSIRO living allowance: AUD$108,328&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Australian Sustainable Agriculture Elite Scholarship: AUD$49,998&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimating Uncertainty in Crop Models</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/phd/ranju/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/phd/ranju/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-ranju&#34;&gt;About Ranju&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ranju is a young researcher originally from Nepal. Ranju&amp;rsquo;s research interest is within the field of water resources considering climate change impact and adaptation in water resources, ecohydrology, and agriculture. She did her Master in Water Engineering and Management at the Asian Institute of Technology and then she worked as Research Associate for three years before starting her Ph.D. at UTAS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Contact:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:Ranju.Chapagain@utas.edu.au&#34;&gt;Ranju.Chapagain@utas.edu.au&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-the-project&#34;&gt;About the project&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project aims to quantify model prediction uncertainty in crop model system using example crops such as potato, for Tasmania and Australia and to test the hypothesis that predicted model outputs vary with the different sources of input, models used for simulation and model parameters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General research question&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do model outputs (e.g. crop yield, water, and energy use efficiency) vary with different inputs, simulation models and model parameters while predicting uncertainty for crop model system using example crops such as potato at a regional and national scale?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Specific research questions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the dominant sources of uncertainty in crop model systems, using potato and wheat as example crops?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How much weight does each uncertainty source contribute to the total uncertainty?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the relative contribution of different sources of uncertainty with crop model systems, using potato as an example crop?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hypotheses&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uncertainty in soil data outweighs uncertainty due to climate and management practices in crop model systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The weight of climate uncertainty is higher than other uncertainty sources in crop model systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ensemble of crop models reduces uncertainty.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objectives&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To assess uncertainty in crop model outputs (crop yield, water use efficiency and energy use efficiency) using example systems such as wheat and potato at state (Tasmania) and national scale.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To investigate the variability of uncertainty over time and space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To determine the contribution made by each source to predict uncertainty.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;location&#34;&gt;Location&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tasmanian Institute of Agriculture, University of Tasmania, Tasmania, Australia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;period&#34;&gt;Period&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From March 2019 to March 2023&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;supervisors&#34;&gt;Supervisors&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr Jonathan Ojeda (primary supervisor), Dr Bec Harris and Dr Tom Remenyi (Geography and Spatial Sciences-UTAS), Dr Neil Huth and Dr Jaci Brown (CSIRO), Prof Caroline Mohammed (TIA-UTAS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;funded-by&#34;&gt;Funded by&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;University of Tasmania and Australian Sustainable Agriculture Elite Scholarship (CSIRO-TIA/UTAS)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;grant-amount&#34;&gt;Grant amount&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Total: AUD$303,226&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UTAS Tuition Fee: AUD$144,900&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tasmania Graduate Research Scholarship living allowance: AUD$108,328&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Australian Sustainable Agriculture Elite Scholarship: AUD$49,998&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
